<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="rview-table.png">
	<name>Run R Model in Microsoft SQL Server</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Run R code with a pre-trained R model on a Microsoft SQL Server in a database.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node allows running R code on a Microsoft SQL Server (using a SQL query behind the scenes).
			Input and output data to the R script are SQL tables. In addition the <b>knime.model</b> (cannot be <b>NULL</b>,
			or will not be transfered to R otherwise) and <b>knime.flow.in</b> variables from a R port can be used in the R script.

			To output data from the R script to the output SQL table, assign a R <b>data.frame</b> to <b>knime.out</b>.

			<h4>JDBC Driver</h4>

			This node requires the <b>Microsoft JDBC driver</b> to be used in the Microsoft SQL Server connector.
			You can install the driver extension from the KNIME Update Site (KNIME Microsoft JDBC Driver For SQL Server).
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Snippet">
			<option name="SQL Input">
				Shows the SQL query defined by the input port. Its result will be available as <b>knime.in</b>.
			</option>
			<option name="SQL Output Table Name">
				Name of the SQL table which <b>knime.out</b> will be written to.
			</option>
			<option name="Overwrite">
				Whether to overwrite when a table with the output table name already exists (failure otherwise).
			</option>
			<option name="R Script">
				The code being executed in R. Input data is available as a data frame named <i>knime.in</i>.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Templates">
			<option name="Category">
				A template category defined by the author.
			</option>
			<option name="Title">
				Names of the available templates.
			</option>
			<option name="Description">
				A brief overview of the purpose of the template.
			</option>
			<option name="Preview">
				The code to be applied to your expression editor.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="R Workspace" index="0" optional="true">R Workspace which contains the model.</inPort>
		<inPort name="Database Connection" index="1">Connection to a Microsoft SQL Database.</inPort>
		<outPort name="Database Connection" index="0">Output Database Connection.</outPort>
	</ports>

	<views>
		<view index="1" name="R Std Output">
			The text sent to standard out during the
			execution of R executable
			as well as the text of the .Rout file
			generated by R.
		</view>
		<view index="0" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable as well as the text of the .Rout file
			generated by R. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>
