<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../r.png" type="Source">
    <name>R Source</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        A source node that reads data from R into KNIME. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        A source node for reading a diversity of data types from R into KNIME tables. Use this when there are R functions 
        that you want to use to read a table into KNIME.  The foreign library provides an example of some such functions.
        <br />
        <br />
        More details about R:<br />
        <br />
        <a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>

        <br />
        <br />
        <a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/foreign/index.html">library(foreign)</a>
        <br />
        <br />
        Read .spss from SPSS
        <br />
        R = read.spss(path_to_spss_file)
        <br />
        <br />
        Read xport from SAS xport format library
        <br />
        R = read.xport(path_to_SAS_xport_file)
        <br />
        <br />
        Read Stata .dta files (binary file format)
        <br />
		R = read.dta(path_to_stata_file)
		<br />
        <br />
        Read dbf from XBase family (Fox Pro et. al)
        <br />
		R = read.dbf(path_to_xbase_file)
		<br />
        <br />
        Read a 'Minitab Portable Worksheet' file
        <br />
		R = read.mtp(path_to_mtp_file)

        </intro>
        		
		<tab name="R Command">
		  <option name ="R Snippet">
            The R commands being executed in R.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="R Binary">
		  <option name ="R binary path">
			Path to the local R executable. Note that it is possible to specify
			the path to the local R executable also in the R section of the 
			KNIME preferences.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Arguments for R binary">
            Add additional arguments run together with the R binary. The 
            '--vanilla' mode ensures a clean workspace and may cause problems 
            when removed.
          </option>
		  <option name="Override default">
			If checked, the specified file is used as R binary. If not checked, 
			the file specified in the KNIME's R preferences is used.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
		
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data that has been sourced from R">A table containing new data from R</outPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
