<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="../r.png">
	<name>R Snippet (Local)</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Allows execution of R commands in a local R installation.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		Allows execution of R commands in a local R installation. The result of 
		these R commands is returned in the output table of this node. All
		input data is written to a CSV file which is then processed together
		with the R commands. The result likewise in the variable R is written
		to CSV file again and then passed into KNIME.<br/>
		Be aware that if you use commands like <code>png()</code> or 
		<code>bmp()</code> etc. you will open a new graphic device to draw 
		the plot to. This means that the graphic device used by this node 
		to display the plot is not used anymore and the view will show a 
		white empty image. 
		</intro>
		<option name ="R binary path">
			Path to the local R executable. Note that it is possible to specify
			the path to the local R executable also in the R section of the 
			KNIME preferences.
		</option>
		<option name ="R command">
			The R commands to run.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<dataIn name="Data Input" index="0">Data Input</dataIn>
		<dataOut name="Data Output" index="0">R Result Data</dataOut>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Standard Out">
			The text sent to standard out during the execution of the external 
			tool. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)<br />
			NOTE: Keeping the view open may slow down the process significantly,
			if it produces a lot of output in a short amount of time.
	    </view>
		<view index="1" name="Error Out">
			The text sent to standard err during the execution of the external 
			tool. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>