<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="./r.png" deprecated="true">
	<name>R Snippet (Remote)</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Allows execution of R commands on an R server. The result of these R 
		commands is returned in the output table of this node. The final result 
		tables' columns are named R1, R2, and so on.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
			Allows execution of R commands on an R server. The entire data 
			(compatible to int, double, and String types) is
			transfered to the R server which then executes a series of R commands
			entered in the dialog. Each column can be accessed by the name provided
			in the input data table. The output has to be assigned to a variable
			named R. Missing values are supported, that is, missing
	 	    values in numeric columns are transfered as <tt>NaN</tt> (Not a 
		    Number) to the R server while missing values in all other types of 
		    columns are sent as <tt>NA</tt>.</p>
			<p><b>R installation:</b><br/>
		    In order to get the R nodes running, you have to install the R-project 
		    first, see <a href="http://www.r-project.org">www.r-project.org</a>.
    	     Also the R server which responds to R commands has to be installed 
    	     and running, see <a href="http://www.rforge.net/Rserve/">
    	     http://www.rforge.net/Rserve/</a>.<br/> 
    	    Also make sure that you have the latest available or compatible 
    	    R-project version at hand. For Windows you may download an R server 
    	    for your R-project version. All other operating systems require the 
    	    most recent clients (R-project installation).
    	    We offer downloads of current 
    	    versions of R and Rserve that are compatible with KNIME on our 
    	    website. Please note that in the current version the R server needs
    	    to be restarted from time to time. If an R node hangs, interrupt 
    	    the R server and restart it. Warnings and errors are printed in the
    	    R server window.
    	    </p>
			<br />
			More details about R:<br />
			<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
			<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Command">
		  <option name="R Snippet">
			Enter R commands here, for instance for computing the Covariance 
			of two columns: <br/>
			<i>R&lt;-cov(Col0,Col1)</i>
		  </option>
		  <option name="Column List">
            The list contains the column that are available in the input table.
            Double click any of the column names to insert the respective field
            in the expression editor. It will replace your current selection or
            simply insert at the current caret position.
          </option>
		  <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Login">
		  <option name ="Host">
			The IP of the computer where the R server is running, for example
			localhost with IP 127.0.0.1 
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Port">
			The port id, default is 6311.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="User">
			The login name can be empty.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Password">
			The password can be empty.
		  </option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Data Input" index="0">Data Input</inPort>
		<outPort name="R Result" index="0">R Result Data</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
