<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="rsnippet.png">
	<name>Add Table To R</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Merges a KNIME table into an R workspace.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
        The data table from the input port is imported into the R workspace as variable <i>knime.in</i>; 
        existing variables are overwritten in case of a conflict.  The node outputs an R workspace 
		containing the updated variables.
		<br /><br />
		More details about R:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Editor">
		  <option name ="R Script">
            The code being executed in R. Code may be executed in full or in part using the 
			Evaluate Script and Evaluate Selection options respectively. Output will be printed to 
			the console.
          </option>
          <option name="Column List">
            The list contains the column that are available in the input table.
            Double click any of the column names to insert the respective field
            in the expression editor. It will replace your current selection or
            simply insert at the current caret position.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently visible to the node. 
			Double clicking any of the entries will insert the respective identifier at
			the current cursor position in your expression editor, replacing the current 
			selection.
          </option>        
	  	</tab>
        <tab name="Templates">
		  <option name ="category">
			A template category defined by the author.
			 
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Title">
			  Name of the template.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Description">
			  A brief overview of the purpose of the template.

          </option>
		  <option name="Preview">
			  The code to be applied to your expression editor.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
        </fullDescription>
	<ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="R Input">R Input</inPort>
	    <inPort index="1" name="Data Input">Data Table Input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="R Output">R Output with appended data</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>