<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="rsnippet.png">
	<name>Add Table To R</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Merges an optional data branch into an R workspace.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
        Merges an optional data branch into an R workspace. 
        The data table from the optional in-port is imported into the R workspace as variable R; 
        existing R variables are overwritten.
		<br /><br />
		More details about R:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Command">
		  <option name ="R Snippet">
            The R commands being executed in R.
          </option>
          <option name="Column List">
            The list contains the column that are available in the input table.
            Double click any of the column names to insert the respective field
            in the expression editor. It will replace your current selection or
            simply insert at the current caret position.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="R Binary">
		  <option name ="R binary path">
			Path to the local R executable. Note that it is possible to specify
			the path to the local R executable also in the R section of the 
			KNIME preferences.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Arguments for R binary">
            Add additional arguments run together with the R binary. The 
            '--vanilla' mode ensures a clean workspace and may cause problems 
            when removed.
          </option>
		  <option name="Override default">
			If checked, the specified file is used as R binary. If not checked, 
			the file specified in the KNIME's R preferences is used.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="R Input">R Input</inPort>
	    <inPort index="1" name="Data Input">Data Table Input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="R Output">R Output with Data</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>