<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Predictor" icon="rsnippet.png">
	<name>R Predictor</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Allows execution of R code in a local R installation for predicting 
		data attributes using new data and an existing model.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		Allows execution of an R script from within KNIME. The resulting table should contain 
		predictions about data attributes based on a model generated with an R Learner node.
		<br /><br />
		More details about R:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Command">
		  <option name ="R Snippet">
            The code being executed in R.  New input data is available as a data frame named <i>knime.in</i>, 
			while the desired model must be available as a variable in the workspace from a previously 
			executed R Learner node.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            variable at the current cursor position.
          </option>
          <option name="Column List">
            The list contains the column references that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position.
          </option>
        </tab>
		<tab name="Templates">
		  <option name ="category">
			A template category defined by the author.
			 
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Title">
			Names of the available templates.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Description">
			A brief overview of the purpose of the template.

          </option>
		  <option name="Preview">
			The code to be applied to your expression editor.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="Model Input">R Model Input</inPort>
	    <inPort index="1" name="Data Input">Data Input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data Output">Predicted data output</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>