<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="rsnippet.png">
	<name>R Source (Workspace)</name>
	
    <shortDescription>
        A source node that reads data from R into KNIME. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        A  node for reading diverse data sources from R into an R Workspace Port. 
		Use this when there are R functions that you want to use to read an exotic file into R but 
		need to branch your workspace in R before bringing it completely into KNIME. The R library 
		"foreign" provides support for some "exotic" data types.  Reasons for needing a workspace branch
		include the generation of multiple visualizations from a single data frame. 
        <br />
        <br />
        More details about R:<br />
        <br />
        <a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>

        <br />
        <br />
        <a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/foreign/index.html">library(foreign)</a>
        </intro>
        		
		<tab name="R Editor">
		  <option name ="R Script">
            The R commands being executed in R. Variables will be saved to the R Workspace port.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Templates">
		  <option name ="category">
			A template category defined by the author.
			 
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Title">
			  Name of the template.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Description">
			  A brief overview of the purpose of the template.

          </option>
		  <option name="Preview">
			  The code to be applied to your expression editor.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="R Worrkspace">A workspace containing new data from within R</outPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>