<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="rsnippet.png" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>R Snippet</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Allows execution of R commands in a local R installation.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		Allows execution of an R script from within KNIME. The result of 
		this script is returned in the output table of this node. 
		<br /><br />
		More details about R:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Editor">
		  <option name ="R Script">
            The code being executed in R.  Input data is available as a data frame named <i>knime.in</i>, 
			while the desired output data must be generated as a data frame named <i>knime.out</i>. Code may
			be executed and re-executed within the script using the Evaluate Script and 
			Evaluate Selection commands respectively.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
          </option>
          <option name="Column List">
            The list contains the column references that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Templates">
		  <option name ="category">
			A template category defined by the author.
			 
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Title">
			  Name of the template.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Description">
			  A brief overview of the purpose of the template.

          </option>
		  <option name="Preview">
			  The code to be applied to your expression editor.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
	    <tab name="Advanced">
	      <option name="NaNs">
	        Convert NaN and +/-Infinity output to missing cells. Enable this for backwards compatibility with the behavior before
	        version 2.10.
	      </option>
	      <option name="Send Row Names to R">
	        Whether to send the row names from KNIME to R. Disabling this can improve performance with very large tables.
	        Row names of knime.in will instead be default R row names: 1:n.
	      </option>
	      <option name="R type for knime.in">
	        By default knime.in is data.frame. For large input tables, using data.table is likely more memory efficient
	        especially while sending the input data to R and may therefore be faster.

	        Please be aware that the <b>support for data.table is experimental (!)</b> and requires the "data.table" R package
	        to be installed. It may not work for some R scripts, may slightly change or even be removed entirely in a future version.
	      </option>
	      <option name="Send batch size">
	        The input of the R node is sent in row batches (default, 10 000 rows at a time). This is the amount of rows KNIME will
	        retain in memory at any given time. For large tables, a higher batch size may be faster, but will require additional
	        memory.
	        Be aware, that R will likely keep all of the input table in memory and this only helps with memory during transmission
	        of data to R.
	      </option>
	    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Data Input" index="0">Data Input</inPort>
		<outPort name="Data Output" index="0">R Result Data</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="R Std Output">
			The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
	    </view>
        <view index="1" name="R Error Output">
            The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
            (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
            failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
        </view>	            
	</views>
</knimeNode>