<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="rtopmml.png">
	<name>R to PMML</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Converts a given R object into a corresponding PMML object.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		Converts a given R object, e.g. as generated by the R Learner node as <i>knime.model</i>, into
		a corresponding PMML object that can then be used together with all 
		KNIME predictors supporting PMML. The R object is first loaded into a 
		new R workspace and then converted into PMML (using the PMML library
		in R). The <tt>toString()</tt> method in R is used to generate a 
		character stream describing the PMML object which is written to the
		PMML out-port.
		<br /><br />
		More details about R and PMML:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">R project</a><br/>
		<a href="http://www.dmg.org/">PMML standard</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Snippet">
          <option name ="R Script">
            The code being executed in R.  Input model should be previously made available in the R 
            workspace as <i>knime.model</i>, while the desired output must be a string named <i>knime.model.pmml</i>.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            variable at the current cursor position.
          </option>
        </tab>
		<tab name="Advanced">
			<option name="Overwrite default path to R home">
				Check this option to select a path to the home of a R installation
				that is different from the path configured on the R preference page.
				The path must point to the root folder of the R installation tree.
				You can either specify the path directly or use the R installation in
				a conda environment. The conda environment can be specified using a conda
				environment flow variable from e.g. a
				<a href="https://kni.me/n/7HrPteTMsla4bZml">&#8220;Conda Environment Propagation&#8221; node.</a>
			</option>
		</tab>
    </fullDescription>
	<ports>
        <inPort name="R Input" index="0">R object generated by a R node</inPort>
        <outPort name="PMML Model Output" index="0">PMML object</outPort>
    </ports>
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
        <view index="1" name="R Error Output">
            The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
            (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
            failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
        </view>
    </views>    
</knimeNode>