<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="rtor.png">
	<name>R To R</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Takes a R workspace and modifies it based on the entered R script.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
        Takes the R workspace from the input port and modifies it according to the 
        entered R script. The node outputs an R workspace containing the updated variables.
		<br /><br />
		More details about R:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="R Snippet">
		  <option name ="R Script">
            The code being executed in R. Code may be executed in full or in part using the Evaluate Script and 
            Evaluate Selection options, respectively. Output is printed to the console.
          </option>
          <option name="Column List">
            The list contains the column that are available in the input table.
            Double click any of the column names to insert the respective field
            in the expression editor. It will replace your current selection or
            simply insert at the current caret position.
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently visible to the node. 
			Double clicking any of the entries will insert the respective identifier at
			the current cursor position in your expression editor, replacing the current 
			selection.
          </option>        
	  	</tab>
        <tab name="Templates">
		  <option name ="Category">
			A template category defined by the author.
			 
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Title">
			  Name of the template.
		  </option>
		  <option name ="Description">
			  A brief overview of the purpose of the template.

          </option>
		  <option name="Preview">
			  The code to be applied to your expression editor.
		  </option>
	    </tab>
	    <tab name="Advanced">
			<option name="Overwrite default path to R home">
				Check this option to select a path to the home of a R installation
				that is different from the path configured on the R preference page.
				The path must point to the root folder of the R installation tree.
				You can either specify the path directly or use the R installation in
				a conda environment. The conda environment can be specified using a conda
				environment flow variable from e.g. a
				<a href="https://kni.me/n/7HrPteTMsla4bZml">&#8220;Conda Environment Propagation&#8221; node.</a>
			</option>
	    </tab>
        </fullDescription>
	<ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="R Workspace">R Input (Workspace)</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="R Workspace">R Output (Workspace)</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>