<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="rsnippet.png" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>R to Table</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Converts an R object into a KNIME data table.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		Converts a data frame from an R workspace into a KNIME data table. 
		The result data is returned at the data out-port.
        
		Please, use the variable name <i>knime.out</i> for the data frame.
		<br /><br />
		More details about R:<br />
		<a href="http://www.r-project.org/">http://www.r-project.org/</a><br />
		<a href="http://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf">Short-refcard.pdf</a>
		</intro>
        <tab name="R Snippet">
          <option name ="R Script">
            <p>The R commands to run. The data frame that
            should appear at the output is expected to be stored in <i>knime.out</i>.</p>
               
            <p>The node also allows to access and modify flow variables. You can access
            all flow variables at <i>knime.flow.in</i> and please add all new or
            modified flow variables to the list at <i>knime.flow.out.</i></p>
            
            <p><b>Examples</b></p>
			<p>Take the input "data" and send it to the ouput:</p>
                     	        
	        <i>knime.out &lt;- data.frame(data)</i>
	                    
            <p>Read the data from the file defined by the flow variable fname:</p>
            <i>data &lt;- read.table(knime.flow.in[["fname"]])</i>
            
            <p>Compute students t-test and store the p-value in the flow variable p.value:</p>
            <i>h &lt;- t.test(knime.in["d"])</i><br/>
			<i>knime.flow.out &lt;- list(p.value = h[["p.value"]])</i>
          </option>
          <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
            the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
            respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Templates">
          <option name="Category - Title">
	          <p>A categorized list of R script templates. The apply button at the left 
	          will replace the R script and guide you to the R Snippet tab.</p>
	          <p>Please use "Create Template..." button on the R Snippet tab to add the
	          current R script to the list of templates.</p>
          </option>
        </tab>
        
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="R Script Editor">
    	Evaluate the R script with input data. Try changes and optionally apply them to the node.
    </interactiveView>	
	<ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="R Input">R Input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data Output">Data Table Output</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
        <view index="0" name="R Std Output">
            The text sent to standard out during the execution of R executable 
            as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
        </view>
		<view index="1" name="R Error Output">
			The text sent to standard error during the execution of R executable 
			as well as the text of the .Rout file generated by R.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously 
			failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>